# VIRGINIA MCCALL

Murfreesboro Tennessee 37128 · 314-783-6012

virginiaamccall@gmail.com · https://virginiamccall.github.io/

Technical multi-tasking professional specializing in SQL, Python, Excel, and Power BI. With a systematic and analytical approach to problem-solving with ability to translate data related concepts. Pursuing a mid-level data analyst position.

## SKILLS

- Technical: Access, Excel, SQL, Tableau, Python, PowerPoint, PostgreSQL, Pivot tables, Excel functions, V-Lookup, H-Lookup, Pivot graphs, NumPy, Seaborn, Plotly, Pandas Matlab Oracle.
- Data Analysis: Web-scraping, data extraction, data cleanup, A/B testing, statistical analysis, risk analyst, presentation design, data visualization, Excel dashboards, Google Analytics, querying.
- Additional Skills: Project management, business strategy, report generation, customer relations, property management (Multifamily/Market/Rad2 Hud Assistance/ Section 42 Tax Credit), communication, organization, detail oriented, root cause analysis, risk management.

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### HR INTERACTIVE DASHBOARD

## PYTHON, SSMS, POWER BI, PERSONAL PROJECT

Using Python, I acquired the Illinois State Employee data found at data. Illinois.gov. I created a connection between python and SSMS then retrieved the data from the SQL server and created a dashboard showing the past 12 years of employment data. View the python <u>code</u> and Power Bi Dashboard.

#### **SHOP QUERY**

## **SQL DATA EXPLORATION, UDEMEY ASSIGNMENT**

Using MySQL, I completed several queries against shop inventory data. The skills used in this project were joins and aggregation functions. View this project here.

#### **WORK ORDER DASHBOARD**

## **EXCEL, PERSONAL PROJECT**

Using sample data from contextures I created a dashboard using power query and power pivot View this project <u>here</u>.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **NOVEMBER 2020 – CURRENT**

# RURAL CARRIER ASSOCIATE, UNITED STATES POSTAL SERVICE

- Provide exemplary customer services
- Coordinate sorting and organization for parcels
- Collaborate with mail team for effective delivery

#### **JUNE 2019-DECEMBER 2020**

PROPERTY MANAGER, SHUKAL & USGAONKAR

- Coordinated the sale of property
- Negotiated cost reducing property upgrades
- Cultivated vendor relationships to maintain property

#### **MARCH 2019-MAY 2020**

# **LEASING / ASSISTANT PROPERTY MANAGER, 159 TINLEY LLC**

- Managed 208 market rate units
- Provided business support for property
- Processed collections, Bank Reconciliations and Payroll
- Collected rental fees, and deposits totaling 350K monthly
- Coordinate the execution of leases at 200% during the height of pandemic

#### **AUGUST 2016-NOVEMBER 2018**

# ASSISTANT PROPERTY MANAGER/ LEASING / MARKETING, ST. CLAIR VILLAGE

- Spearheaded property marketing and screening
- Maintain accounting records and executed collections
- Organized tenant files utilizing Yardi Voyager/Rent Café/Bluemoon
- Oversaw groundskeepers, maintenance, and improvements of 115 units
- Analyze bids from contractors for property provision services resulting in a 3% decrease in expenses.

## **EDUCATION**

**DECEMENR 2014 • COMMENCED** 

## **B.A. ACTUARIAL SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF NORTHERN IOWA**

Undergraduate research on the mathematical modeling of SARS data using Matlab.

SEPTEMBER 2022 • NOVEMBER 2022

FULL STACK DATA ANALYST BOOTCAMP, UDEMEY

2